<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-30T17:44:18+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/</id><title type="html">Galaxy Europe</title><subtitle>The European Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Convert mass spectrometry data file formats with msconvert</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/24/msconvert/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Convert mass spectrometry data file formats with msconvert" /><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/24/msconvert</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/24/msconvert/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/galaxyp/msconvert/msconvert/3.0.19052.0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;msconvert&lt;/a&gt; is a tool to
convert mass spectrometry data file formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of supported file formats is given below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;agilentbrukeryep.d.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;agilentmasshunter.d.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;brukerbaf.d.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;brukertdf.d.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watersmasslynx.raw.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;thermo.raw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wiff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wiff.tar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mzml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mzxml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mz5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mgf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ms2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is special in multiple ways. At first its one of the few tools that only runs in a very special Container, created by Dr. Matt Chambers, including
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org/&quot;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.proteowizard.org/&quot;&gt;Proteowizard&lt;/a&gt;. This is because many of the underlying libraries do need a Windows runtime environment
and Matt found a way to make this available in a Container so Galaxy Europe and all others can use it on there Cloud systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/galaxyp/msconvert/msconvert/3.0.19052.0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;msconvert&lt;/a&gt; is part of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.proteowizard.org/&quot;&gt;Proteowizard&lt;/a&gt; you need to agree with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.proteowizard.org/licenses.html&quot;&gt;vendor licenses&lt;/a&gt; before you can use this tool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="release" /><summary type="html">msconvert is a tool to convert mass spectrometry data file formats.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UseGalaxy.eu update to 19.01</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/19/galaxy-1901/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UseGalaxy.eu update to 19.01" /><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/19/galaxy-1901</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/19/galaxy-1901/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve updated our Galaxy server to version 19.01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;galaxy-upgrade&quot;&gt;Galaxy Upgrade&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had expected this to be a short downtime since upgrades have been
increasingly smooth since 18.09. Unfortunately for reasons we are still
investigating the upgraded version did not funtion with our server setup. We
have updated our system to respond to this, and after some downtime Galaxy is
again online. We apologise for the inconvenience this has caused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest Galaxy release includes lots of awesome new features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revised UI Style&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy styling has been substantially reworked resulting in the largest visual refresh to Galaxy in years. It should provide a much cleaner and more consistent interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/19.01-revised-ui.png&quot; alt=&quot;Revised UI style cleans up the UI to be more consistent and clear&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Colourful Tags&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you use dataset name tags (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#tag&lt;/code&gt;), they will randomly be assigned a color. The colors are consistent; anywhere that tag with the same text appears in your history, it will have the same color. This should increase visual distinction between similarly shaped words, making it easier to track data flow in complex analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/19.01-colourful-tags.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tags are now randomly assigned a consistent colour, helping you to distinguish between similarly shaped words&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensive Workflow Enhancements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workflow editor now features new tool-like inputs which provide non-file data (such as numbers, text, true/false, colors) which can be connected to tool inputs. You are no longer restricted to only using files as inputs to tools!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/19.01-new-wf-inputs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Workflow inputs are available at the top of the workflow editor menu, under &amp;quot;Inputs&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workflow editor allows you to specify that specific inputs should be exposed, and can thus be connected to the new workflow inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/19.01-new-wf-types.png&quot; alt=&quot;The new inputs can be assigned a data type&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Help Site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a new discussion forum to replace Biostars. It is accessible under the ‘Help’ menu on some Galaxies, or at https://help.galaxyproject.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/19.01-help-site.png&quot; alt=&quot;Galaxy's new help forum which replaces biostars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>erasche</name></author><category term="release" /><summary type="html">We’ve updated our Galaxy server to version 19.01.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UseGalaxy.eu Downtime on 18th March</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/18/galaxy-downtime/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UseGalaxy.eu Downtime on 18th March" /><published>2019-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/18/galaxy-downtime</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/18/galaxy-downtime/">&lt;p&gt;A normal upgrade went awry and we had to restore some data from backup. We had a total downtime of around 20 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;incident-timeline&quot;&gt;Incident Timeline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;State&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We began the upgrade procedure, expecting it to proceed smoothly&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18:45&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A database migration fails in a bad way. Attempts to recover the situation were not successful. We decide to restore from backup.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19:45&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Backup restore finishes. It was made minutes too late. We decide to re-restore from the most recent backup, and manually extract the needed table from the previous backup.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20:30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We updated our website to reflect the current situation.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We manage to get the database in a partially functional state and debug a problem with zerglings where they refuse to serve 19.01.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 18&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;22:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Due to stress of the incident, Helena identifies that it is likely her error rate will increase if she continues working, maybe with disastrous consequences and stops for the evening.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;08:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Helena recovers the broken table and manually applies the database migration.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We discover additional issues with the new options, namely some upstream bugs we accidentally triggered. The server is kept closed until these issues are resolved.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;March 19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11:40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;UseGalaxy.eu is back online&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;workflow_step_connection&lt;/code&gt; table was partially corrupted as part of the
failed migration. It is likely that had we not tried to re-run upgrades, and
had not tried to manually apply the table changes, we could have prevented the
small loss of any new workflow connections created on Monday. We cannot say
this for certain, but it is probably. In the future we can do a lot to
safeguard against similar errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resolution&quot;&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have planned since some time that we will have a test Galaxy where we can
test out these upgrades ahead of time, but unfortunately it has not been
possible to allocate time to this project, given the current priority/urgency
matrix. This task will be re-prioritised following this incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will adjust our backup procedures before upgrades. Currently given the
extremely positive experiences and relative safety of database migrations in
the past years of running UseGalaxy.eu, we do not make backups before an
upgrade, and rely only on the normal daily backups. We will investigate the
possibility to trigger a backup immediately before any database changes, to
prevent similar issues in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a significant interruption to our services for what should have been a
simple upgrade. We apologise for the inconvenience this has caused.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>erasche</name></author><category term="devops" /><category term="downtime" /><summary type="html">A normal upgrade went awry and we had to restore some data from backup. We had a total downtime of around 20 hours.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper - Biomolecular Reaction and Interaction Dynamics Global Environment (BRIDGE)</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/15/bridge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper - Biomolecular Reaction and Interaction Dynamics Global Environment (BRIDGE)" /><published>2019-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/15/bridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/15/bridge/">&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with our cooperation partner at the Scientific Computing Research Unit, University of Cape Town, we have recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/advance-article/doi/10.1093/bioinformatics/btz107/5317160&quot;&gt;“Biomolecular Reaction and Interaction Dynamics Global Environment (BRIDGE)”&lt;/a&gt;. This publication provides a basis for performing molecular dynamics simulations and analysis through Galaxy, using a number of commonly used packages, such as NAMD, GROMACS and CHARMM (for simulation) and Bio3D and MDAnalysis (for analysis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concurrently, we are publishing a new flavor of Galaxy for computational chemistry (located &lt;a href=&quot;https://cheminformatics.usegalaxy.eu/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) which we will continue to develop by adding further molecular dynamics and cheminformatics tools. We hope you find it useful - any feedback is appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The pathway from genomics through proteomics and onto a molecular description of biochemical processes makes the discovery of drugs and biomaterials possible. A research framework common to genomics and proteomics is needed to conduct biomolecular simulations that will connect biological data to the dynamic molecular mechanisms of enzymes and proteins. Novice biomolecular modelers are faced with the daunting task of complex setups and a myriad of possible choices preventing their use of molecular simulations and their ability to conduct reliable and reproducible computations that can be shared with collaborators and verified for procedural accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We present the foundations of Biomolecular Reaction and Interaction Dynamics Global Environment (BRIDGE) developed on the Galaxy platform that makes possible fundamental molecular dynamics of proteins through workflows and pipelines via commonly used packages, such as NAMD, GROMACS and CHARMM. BRIDGE can be used to set up and simulate biological macromolecules, perform conformational analysis from trajectory data and conduct data analytics of large scale protein motions using statistical rigor. We illustrate the basic BRIDGE simulation and analytics capabilities on a previously reported CBH1 protein simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability and implementation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Publicly available at https://github.com/scientificomputing/BRIDGE and https://usegalaxy.eu&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplementary information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Supplementary data are available at Bioinformatics online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">In collaboration with our cooperation partner at the Scientific Computing Research Unit, University of Cape Town, we have recently published “Biomolecular Reaction and Interaction Dynamics Global Environment (BRIDGE)”. This publication provides a basis for performing molecular dynamics simulations and analysis through Galaxy, using a number of commonly used packages, such as NAMD, GROMACS and CHARMM (for simulation) and Bio3D and MDAnalysis (for analysis).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper The Chimera and the Cyborg</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/14/chimera-and-the-cyborg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper The Chimera and the Cyborg" /><published>2019-03-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/14/chimera-and-the-cyborg</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/14/chimera-and-the-cyborg/">&lt;p&gt;Our admin Helena, in collaboration with the Rechenzentrum Uni Freiburg, has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://astesj.com/v04/i02/p01/&quot;&gt;“The Chimera and the Cyborg: Hybrid Compute: In vivo HPC, Cloud and Container Implementations”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;High Performance Computing (HPC) systems offer excellent metrics for speed and efficiency when using bare metal hardware, a high speed interconnects, and massively parallel applications. However, this leaves out a significant portion of scientific computational tasks, namely high throughput computing tasks that can be trivially parallelized and scientific workflows that require their own well-defined software environments. Cloud computing provides such management and implementation flexibility at the expense of a tolerable fraction of performance. We show two approaches to make HPC resources available in a dynamically reconfigurable hybrid HPC/Cloud architecture. Both can be achieved with few modifications to existing HPC/Cloud environments. The first approach, from the University of Melbourne, generates a consistent compute node operating system image with variation in the virtual hardware specification. The second approach, from the University of Freiburg, deploys a cloud-client on the HPC compute nodes, so the HPC hardware can run Cloud-Workloads using the scheduling and accounting facilities of the HPC system. Extensive use of these production systems provides evidence of the validity of either approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Our admin Helena, in collaboration with the Rechenzentrum Uni Freiburg, has published “The Chimera and the Cyborg: Hybrid Compute: In vivo HPC, Cloud and Container Implementations”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galactic News</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galactic News" /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news/">&lt;p&gt;Find a summary of what is going on in the Galaxy community in March 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="galaxy" /><summary type="html">Find a summary of what is going on in the Galaxy community in March 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A(nother) successful Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop in Freiburg</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A(nother) successful Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop in Freiburg" /><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 5 day workshop on HTS data analysis in Freiburg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/2019-03-04-galaxy-hts-workshop.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;A successful Galaxy workshop in Freiburga&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this week, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/freiburg/&quot;&gt;Freiburg Galaxy Team&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ie-freiburg.mpg.de/bioinformaticsfac&quot;&gt;Bionformatics facility from the MPI-IE Freiburg&lt;/a&gt; offered an introductory course to the analysis of high-throughput sequencing data using Galaxy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monday 25th: HTS and Galaxy presentations and introduction by Thomas Manke and Björn, with the help of Anika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesday 26th: Quality control, Mapping, ChIP-seq analysis by Bérénice and Leily Rabbani, with the help of Devon Ryan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednesday 27th: RNA-seq analysis by Anika and Bérénice, with the help of Mehmet and Anup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursday 28th: HiC data analysis by Devon Ryan and Joachim, with the help of Björn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friday 1st: Exercises &amp;amp; discussion with Björn and Bérénice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Master student, 17 PhD students, 8 Post-docs and 1 PIs participated to this workshop. 
The feedback we received is good: all but one of the participants though it was good to excellent and will recommend it and all will use Galaxy for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had during this week special guests, as part of cooperation with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.uni-freiburg.de/cognition&quot;&gt;Center of Cognitive Science&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uni-freiburg.de/?set_language=en&quot;&gt;University of Freiburg&lt;/a&gt;. They are conducting an usability evaluation of Galaxy and used this workshop to evaluate how new users use Galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;twitter-moment&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/moments/1102590890902806529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop (February 2019)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 5 day workshop on HTS data analysis in Freiburg!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells.”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells.&quot;" /><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz/">&lt;p&gt;Johanna M. Walz et al. published about the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0014483518305037&quot;&gt;“Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Johanna and her team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt; Human retinal microvascular endothelial cells (HRMVECs) are involved in the pathogenesis of
retinopathy of prematurity. In this study, the microRNA (miRNA) expression profiles of
HRMVECs were investigated under resting conditions, angiogenic stimulation (VEGF treatment) and anti-VEGF treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/strong&gt; The miRNA profiles of HRMVECs under resting and angiogenic conditions (VEGF treatment),
as well as after addition of aflibercept, bevacizumab or ranibizumab were evaluated by analyzing the transcriptome
of small non-coding RNAs. Differentially expressed miRNAs were validated using qPCR and classified using Gene Ontology enrichment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt; Ten miRNAs were found to be significantly changed more than 2-fold. Seven of these miRNAs were
changed between resting conditions and angiogenic stimulation. Four of these miRNAs (miR-139-5p/-3p and miR-335-5p/-3p) were validated by qPCR in independent experiments and 
were found to be associated with angiogenesis and cell migration in Gene Ontology analysis. In addition, analysis of the most abundant miRNAs in the HRMVEC miRNome (representing 
at least 1% of the miRNome) was conducted and identified miR-21-5p, miR-29a-3p, miR-100-5p and miR-126-5p/-3p to be differently expressed by at least 15% between resting 
conditions and angiogenic conditions. These miRNAs were found to be associated with apoptotic signaling, regulation of kinase activity, intracellular signal transduction, cell 
surface receptor signaling and positive regulation of cell differentiation in Gene Ontology analysis. No differentially regulated miRNAs between angiogenic stimulation and 
angiogenic stimulation plus anti-VEGF treatment were identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt; In this study we characterized the miRNA profile of HRMVECs under resting, angiogenic and anti-angiogenic conditions and identified several miRNAs of potential 
pathophysiologic importance for angioproliferative retinal diseases. Our results have implications for possible miRNA-targeted angiomodulatory approaches in diseases like 
diabetic retinopathy or retinopathy of prematurity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Johanna M. Walz et al. published about the “Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation.”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation.&quot;" /><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3/">&lt;p&gt;Marina Veil, Lev Yampolsky and Daria Onichtchouk found that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://genome.cshlp.org/content/early/2019/01/23/gr.240572.118.abstract&quot;&gt;“Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Marina, Lev and Daria!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The zebrafish embryo is mostly transcriptionally quiescent during the first 10 cell cycles,
until the main wave of Zygotic Genome Activation (ZGA) occurs, accompanied by fast chromatin remodeling.
At ZGA, homologs of mammalian stem cell transcription factors (TFs) Pou5f3, Nanog and Sox19b
bind to thousands of developmental enhancers to initiate transcription. So far, how these
TFs influence chromatin dynamics at ZGA has remained unresolved. To address this question,
we analyzed nucleosome positions in wild-type and Maternal-Zygotic (MZ) mutants for pou5f3
and nanog by MNase-seq. We show that Nanog, Sox19b, and Pou5f3 bind to the High Nucleosome
Affinity Regions (HNARs). HNARs are spanning over 600 bp, featuring high in vivo and
predicted in vitro nucleosome occupancy and high predicted propeller twist DNA shape value.
We suggest a two-step nucleosome destabilization-depletion model, where the same intrinsic
DNA properties of HNAR promote both high nucleosome occupancy and differential binding of
TFs. In the first step, already prior to ZGA, Pou5f3 and Nanog destabilize nucleosomes on
HNAR centers genome-wide. In the second step, post-ZGA, Nanog, Pou5f3, and SoxB1 maintain
open chromatin state on the subset of HNARs, acting synergistically. Nanog binds to the
HNAR center, while the Pou5f3 stabilizes the flanks. The HNAR model will provide a useful
tool for genome regulatory studies in the variety of biological systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/daria_2019.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Marina Veil, Lev Yampolsky and Daria Onichtchouk found that “Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tool Quest: Do you know the answer?</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tool Quest: Do you know the answer?" /><published>2019-02-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest/">&lt;p&gt;Last week we got a request from on of our users with a tricky question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I need a tool that:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;reads two files (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I need to pick out random lines from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;but it should ignore lines in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;.
And the number of random lines to be picked should be equal to the number of lines in the subset file.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Two example files are attached:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Parent&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;abcd
bcde
cdef
defg
efgh
fghi
ghij
hijk
ijkl
jklm
klmn
lmno
mnop
nopq
opqr
pqrs
qrst
rstu
stuv
tuvw
uvwx
vwxy
wxyz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; (is a subset of the parent file):&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hijk
ijkl
jklm
opqr
pqrs
qrst
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any idea how to solve that? It is possible with the normal Galaxy tools :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We proposed the following solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_easyjoin_tool/&quot;&gt;“Join two files”&lt;/a&gt;
  to filter out the lines that are in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; file. You should have now a new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; file without those line from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_sort_header_tool/&quot;&gt;“Sort”&lt;/a&gt;
  the new file with the option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Random order (-R)&lt;/code&gt;. Sort has indeed a random sorting option, somehow unintuitive - but useful.&lt;br /&gt;
  Now we have a random sorted file without the unwanted lines. What needs to be done is to extract N lines, where N is the length of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=addValue&quot;&gt;“Add column to an existing dataset”&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iterate&lt;/code&gt; option enabled. This you need to do
  for both files the initial &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file and the new random sorted partent from step 2.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now use &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_easyjoin_tool/&quot;&gt;“Join two files”&lt;/a&gt;
  again, but this time on the newly created datasets with the additional column. This will give you exactly N lines where N is the amount of
  lines in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Optional) If needed, remove the additional column with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_cut_tool/1.1.0&quot;&gt;Cut tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Last week we got a request from on of our users with a tricky question:</summary></entry></feed>