<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-05T02:15:41+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/</id><title type="html">Galaxy Europe</title><subtitle>The European Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Galactic News</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galactic News" /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/05/galactic-news/">&lt;p&gt;Find a summary of what is going on in the Galaxy community in March 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="galaxy" /><summary type="html">Find a summary of what is going on in the Galaxy community in March 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A(nother) successful Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop in Freiburg</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A(nother) successful Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop in Freiburg" /><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/03/04/galaxy-hts-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 5 day workshop on HTS data analysis in Freiburg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/2019-03-04-galaxy-hts-workshop.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;A successful Galaxy workshop in Freiburga&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this week, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/freiburg/&quot;&gt;Freiburg Galaxy Team&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ie-freiburg.mpg.de/bioinformaticsfac&quot;&gt;Bionformatics facility from the MPI-IE Freiburg&lt;/a&gt; offered an introductory course to the analysis of high-throughput sequencing data using Galaxy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monday 25th: HTS and Galaxy presentations and introduction by Thomas Manke and Björn, with the help of Anika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesday 26th: Quality control, Mapping, ChIP-seq analysis by Bérénice and Leily Rabbani, with the help of Devon Ryan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednesday 27th: RNA-seq analysis by Anika and Bérénice, with the help of Mehmet and Anup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursday 28th: HiC data analysis by Devon Ryan and Joachim, with the help of Björn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friday 1st: Exercises &amp;amp; discussion with Björn and Bérénice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Master student, 17 PhD students, 8 Post-docs and 1 PIs participated to this workshop. 
The feedback we received is good: all but one of the participants though it was good to excellent and will recommend it and all will use Galaxy for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had during this week special guests, as part of cooperation with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.uni-freiburg.de/cognition&quot;&gt;Center of Cognitive Science&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uni-freiburg.de/?set_language=en&quot;&gt;University of Freiburg&lt;/a&gt;. They are conducting an usability evaluation of Galaxy and used this workshop to evaluate how new users use Galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;twitter-moment&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/moments/1102590890902806529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;Galaxy HTS data analysis workshop (February 2019)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 5 day workshop on HTS data analysis in Freiburg!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells.”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells.&quot;" /><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Walz/">&lt;p&gt;Johanna M. Walz et al. published about the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0014483518305037&quot;&gt;“Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Carolin and her team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt; Human retinal microvascular endothelial cells (HRMVECs) are involved in the pathogenesis of
retinopathy of prematurity. In this study, the microRNA (miRNA) expression profiles of
HRMVECs were investigated under resting conditions, angiogenic stimulation (VEGF treatment) and anti-VEGF treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/strong&gt; The miRNA profiles of HRMVECs under resting and angiogenic conditions (VEGF treatment),
as well as after addition of aflibercept, bevacizumab or ranibizumab were evaluated by analyzing the transcriptome
of small non-coding RNAs. Differentially expressed miRNAs were validated using qPCR and classified using Gene Ontology enrichment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt; Ten miRNAs were found to be significantly changed more than 2-fold. Seven of these miRNAs were
changed between resting conditions and angiogenic stimulation. Four of these miRNAs (miR-139-5p/-3p and miR-335-5p/-3p) were validated by qPCR in independent experiments and 
were found to be associated with angiogenesis and cell migration in Gene Ontology analysis. In addition, analysis of the most abundant miRNAs in the HRMVEC miRNome (representing 
at least 1% of the miRNome) was conducted and identified miR-21-5p, miR-29a-3p, miR-100-5p and miR-126-5p/-3p to be differently expressed by at least 15% between resting 
conditions and angiogenic conditions. These miRNAs were found to be associated with apoptotic signaling, regulation of kinase activity, intracellular signal transduction, cell 
surface receptor signaling and positive regulation of cell differentiation in Gene Ontology analysis. No differentially regulated miRNAs between angiogenic stimulation and 
angiogenic stimulation plus anti-VEGF treatment were identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt; In this study we characterized the miRNA profile of HRMVECs under resting, angiogenic and anti-angiogenic conditions and identified several miRNAs of potential 
pathophysiologic importance for angioproliferative retinal diseases. Our results have implications for possible miRNA-targeted angiomodulatory approaches in diseases like 
diabetic retinopathy or retinopathy of prematurity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Johanna M. Walz et al. published about the “Impact of angiogenic activation and inhibition on miRNA profiles of human retinal endothelial cells”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation.”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation.&quot;" /><published>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/11/Veil-Pou5f3/">&lt;p&gt;Marina Veil, Lev Yampolsky and Daria Onichtchouk found that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://genome.cshlp.org/content/early/2019/01/23/gr.240572.118.abstract&quot;&gt;“Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Marina, Lev and Daria!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The zebrafish embryo is mostly transcriptionally quiescent during the first 10 cell cycles,
until the main wave of Zygotic Genome Activation (ZGA) occurs, accompanied by fast chromatin remodeling.
At ZGA, homologs of mammalian stem cell transcription factors (TFs) Pou5f3, Nanog and Sox19b
bind to thousands of developmental enhancers to initiate transcription. So far, how these
TFs influence chromatin dynamics at ZGA has remained unresolved. To address this question,
we analyzed nucleosome positions in wild-type and Maternal-Zygotic (MZ) mutants for pou5f3
and nanog by MNase-seq. We show that Nanog, Sox19b, and Pou5f3 bind to the High Nucleosome
Affinity Regions (HNARs). HNARs are spanning over 600 bp, featuring high in vivo and
predicted in vitro nucleosome occupancy and high predicted propeller twist DNA shape value.
We suggest a two-step nucleosome destabilization-depletion model, where the same intrinsic
DNA properties of HNAR promote both high nucleosome occupancy and differential binding of
TFs. In the first step, already prior to ZGA, Pou5f3 and Nanog destabilize nucleosomes on
HNAR centers genome-wide. In the second step, post-ZGA, Nanog, Pou5f3, and SoxB1 maintain
open chromatin state on the subset of HNARs, acting synergistically. Nanog binds to the
HNAR center, while the Pou5f3 stabilizes the flanks. The HNAR model will provide a useful
tool for genome regulatory studies in the variety of biological systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/daria_2019.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Marina Veil, Lev Yampolsky and Daria Onichtchouk found that “Pou5f3, SoxB1, and Nanog remodel chromatin on High Nucleosome Affinity Regions at Zygotic Genome Activation”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tool Quest: Do you know the answer?</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tool Quest: Do you know the answer?" /><published>2019-02-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/02/09/tool-quest/">&lt;p&gt;Last week we got a request from on of our users with a tricky question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I need a tool that:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;reads two files (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I need to pick out random lines from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;but it should ignore lines in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;.
And the number of random lines to be picked should be equal to the number of lines in the subset file.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Two example files are attached:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Parent&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;abcd
bcde
cdef
defg
efgh
fghi
ghij
hijk
ijkl
jklm
klmn
lmno
mnop
nopq
opqr
pqrs
qrst
rstu
stuv
tuvw
uvwx
vwxy
wxyz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; (is a subset of the parent file):&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hijk
ijkl
jklm
opqr
pqrs
qrst
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any idea how to solve that? It is possible with the normal Galaxy tools :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We proposed the following solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_easyjoin_tool/&quot;&gt;“Join two files”&lt;/a&gt;
  to filter out the lines that are in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; file. You should have now a new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;parent&lt;/code&gt; file without those line from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_sort_header_tool/&quot;&gt;“Sort”&lt;/a&gt;
  the new file with the option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Random order (-R)&lt;/code&gt;. Sort has indeed a random sorting option, somehow unintuitive - but useful.&lt;br /&gt;
  Now we have a random sorted file without the unwanted lines. What needs to be done is to extract N lines, where N is the length of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=addValue&quot;&gt;“Add column to an existing dataset”&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iterate&lt;/code&gt; option enabled. This you need to do
  for both files the initial &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file and the new random sorted partent from step 2.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now use &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_easyjoin_tool/&quot;&gt;“Join two files”&lt;/a&gt;
  again, but this time on the newly created datasets with the additional column. This will give you exactly N lines where N is the amount of
  lines in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subset&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Optional) If needed, remove the additional column with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/text_processing/tp_cut_tool/1.1.0&quot;&gt;Cut tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Last week we got a request from on of our users with a tricky question:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vote for the Training during the next Galaxy Community Conference</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/27/GCC-training-vote/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vote for the Training during the next Galaxy Community Conference" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/27/GCC-training-vote</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/27/GCC-training-vote/">&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy Community Conference starts with training but also continues with training throughout the conference.
The community proposed some topics and now &lt;strong&gt;you need to vote&lt;/strong&gt; to select the ones offered at GCC2019!
&lt;strong&gt;Please take a few minutes to vote which ones should be offered at GCC2019! Thank you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">The Galaxy Community Conference starts with training but also continues with training throughout the conference. The community proposed some topics and now you need to vote to select the ones offered at GCC2019! Please take a few minutes to vote which ones should be offered at GCC2019! Thank you!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learn how the NASA uses Galaxy!</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/26/NASA-Galaxy-and-training/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn how the NASA uses Galaxy!" /><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/26/NASA-Galaxy-and-training</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/26/NASA-Galaxy-and-training/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.org/people/dave-bouvier/&quot;&gt;Dave B&lt;/a&gt; pointed us to this nice article about
“Exploring the Effects of Spaceflight on Mouse Physiology using the Open Access NASA GeneLab Platform”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Open Access NASA GeneLab Platform” is a Galaxy instance and they referencing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://training.galaxyproject.org/&quot;&gt;Galaxy Project Training Material&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA and Galaxy Project - what a nice match!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Dave B pointed us to this nice article about “Exploring the Effects of Spaceflight on Mouse Physiology using the Open Access NASA GeneLab Platform”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy enhances Introduction to Genomics as part of Master program in Belgrade, by Nevena Veljkovic</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/feedback-genomics-master-course/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy enhances Introduction to Genomics as part of Master program in Belgrade, by Nevena Veljkovic" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/feedback-genomics-master-course</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/feedback-genomics-master-course/">&lt;p&gt;This semester, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bg.ac.rs/en/members/faculties/FB.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Faculty of Biology at the University of Belgrade&lt;/a&gt; offered for the first time
an elective master course &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Genomics&lt;/strong&gt; which included several hands-on sessions on the Galaxy platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lectures in this course were open to everyone and soon after the hands-on sessions 
started, several PhD students joined the 8 master students attending the course. During the classes we worked on RNA-seq analyses and variant calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students were interested and deeply engaged. In the end, this first generation completed the course
with excellent marks and was (based on their feedback) satisfied with the perspective in data science 
that Galaxy has opened to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Galaxy project team was very helpful in providing the training resources (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.eu/tiaas&quot;&gt;TIaaS&lt;/a&gt;)
and in responding to our questions. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nevena Veljkovic, lecturer &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Genomics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">This semester, the Faculty of Biology at the University of Belgrade offered for the first time an elective master course Introduction to Genomics which included several hands-on sessions on the Galaxy platform.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The GOEnrichment tool and tutorial are now available on Galaxy, by Daniel Sobral</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/GOEnrichment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The GOEnrichment tool and tutorial are now available on Galaxy, by Daniel Sobral" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/GOEnrichment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/25/GOEnrichment/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/goenrichment/goenrichment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GOEnrichment&lt;/a&gt; is a tool for performing GO enrichment analysis of gene sets, such as those obtained from RNA-seq or Microarray experiments, to help characterize them at the functional level.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/transcriptomics/tutorials/goenrichment/tutorial.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A tutorial&lt;/a&gt; for the tool is also available
at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Galaxy Project training website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/goenrichment_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/goenrichment/goenrichment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GOEnrichment&lt;/a&gt; is flexible in that it allows the user to use any version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geneontology.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gene Ontology&lt;/a&gt; and any &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geneontology.org/page/download-go-annotations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GO annotation&lt;/a&gt; file they desire. To enable the use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geneontology.org/page/go-subset-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GO slims&lt;/a&gt;,
it is accompanied by a sister tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/goslimmer/goslimmer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GOSlimmer&lt;/a&gt;, which can convert annotation files from full GO to any specified GO slim.
The tool features an optional graph clustering algorithm to reduce the redundancy in the set of enriched GO terms and simplify its output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was developed by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://biodata.pt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BioData.pt/ELIXIR-PT&lt;/a&gt; team at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igc.gulbenkian.pt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instituto Gulbenkian de Ciência&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also used as a case study to test the full pipeline of integrating a tool in Galaxy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrating the GOEnrichment and GOSlimmer tools in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bioconda.github.io/contribute-a-recipe.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bioconda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrapping the tools for Galaxy, and integrate them in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyproject/tools-iuc/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IUC tool collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing the tutorial and integrate it in the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/galaxyproject/training-material&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Galaxy tutorial repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="release" /><summary type="html">GOEnrichment is a tool for performing GO enrichment analysis of gene sets, such as those obtained from RNA-seq or Microarray experiments, to help characterize them at the functional level. A tutorial for the tool is also available at the Galaxy Project training website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A successful Galaxy RNA-seq workshop in Belgrade</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/19/rna-seq-workshop-belgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A successful Galaxy RNA-seq workshop in Belgrade" /><published>2019-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/19/rna-seq-workshop-belgrade</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2019/01/19/rna-seq-workshop-belgrade/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 2 day course in the beautiful city of Belgrade!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/134305289@N03/32922648008/in/shares-7s06ku/&quot; title=&quot;Galaxy RNA-seq workshop @ Belgrad&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7876/32922648008_1371ba32d5_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; alt=&quot;Galaxy RNA-seq workshop @ Belgrad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 2 day workshop was organized and hosted by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bg.ac.rs/en/members/institutes/Vinca.php&quot;&gt;Institute of Nuclear Sciences Vinča&lt;/a&gt; in Belgrade. Björn, Helena and Bérénice offered an introductory course to Galaxy and RNA-seq data analysis for the 50 participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the nice feedback we received, all of the participants seem to have enjoyed this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/2019-01-19-rna-seq-workshop-belgrade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Feedbacks stickers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Nevena and Vlada for the invitation and the sightseeing ❤️!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;check-out-more-activity-about-this-event&quot;&gt;Check out more activity about this event&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/134305289@N03/32922649378/in/shares-7s06ku/&quot; title=&quot;Galaxy RNA-seq workshop @ Belgrad&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7813/32922649378_f14c7096bd_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; alt=&quot;Galaxy RNA-seq workshop @ Belgrad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;jekyll-twitter-plugin&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;twitter-moment&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/moments/1086591402081964033?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;Galaxy RNA-seq workshop (January 2019)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Last week, the Freiburg Galaxy team taught a 2 day course in the beautiful city of Belgrade!</summary></entry></feed>