<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-07T14:44:59+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/</id><title type="html">Galaxy Europe</title><subtitle>The European Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Upcoming Server Migration</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/07/migration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upcoming Server Migration" /><published>2018-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/07/migration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/07/migration/">&lt;p&gt;We will be migrating Galaxy to new hardware. The hardware acting as the ‘head
node’ is reaching End-of-Life and needs to be decomissioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to execute this migration on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arewemeetingyet.com/Berlin/2018-11-12/13:00/UseGalaxy.eu%20Server%20Migration&quot;&gt;Monday, 2018-11-12 at around 13 CET&lt;/a&gt;.
This migration &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be completely transparent to all end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;migration-plan&quot;&gt;Migration Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have deployed the new head node and have been testing it over the past
months, correcting issues as we have come across them. We had an internal hack
day where team members tested the new server heavily and identified issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-striped&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;November 7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We freeze configuration changes and any tool installation in both Galaxies. &lt;a href=&quot;https://build.galaxyproject.eu/job/usegalaxy-eu/job/install-tools/&quot;&gt;Automated tool installation&lt;/a&gt; has been disabled.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;November 8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We swap the beta backend server from our testing database to our production database, and run some testing against it.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;November 12&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We update our proxy to direct traffic to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;usegalaxy.eu&lt;/code&gt; to the new backend server&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;November 19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We stop the Galaxy processes on the old head node, retaining it for another few weeks to ensure we have not missed anything&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backout-plan&quot;&gt;Backout Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extremely important part of any big migration with far reaching impacts is the backout plan. What will we do if something goes wrong? For this migration, the backout plan is extremely simple: we reconfigure the proxy to use the old server as the backend for usegalaxy.eu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a safe fallback position in the face of any complications. Traffic will temporarily be split between the instances, but since Galaxy maintains session state in the database, this should not present any issues.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><summary type="html">We will be migrating Galaxy to new hardware. The hardware acting as the ‘head node’ is reaching End-of-Life and needs to be decomissioned.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus Has No Major Influence on the Platelet Transcriptome”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/05/ThomasNuehrenberg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus Has No Major Influence on the Platelet Transcriptome&quot;" /><published>2018-11-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/05/ThomasNuehrenberg</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/05/ThomasNuehrenberg/">&lt;p&gt;In a new manuscript Thomas Nührenberg et al. found that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/8989252&quot;&gt;“Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus Has No Major Influence on the Platelet Transcriptome”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Thomas and his team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Diabetes mellitus (DM) has been associated with increased platelet reactivity as well
as increased levels of platelet RNAs in plasma. Here, we sought to evaluate whether the platelet
transcriptome is altered in the presence of uncontrolled DM. Methods. Next-generation sequencing
(NGS) was performed on platelet RNA for 5 patients with uncontrolled DM (HbA1c 9.0%) and 5 control
patients (HbA1c 5.5%) with otherwise similar clinical characteristics. RNA was isolated from
leucocyte-depleted platelet-rich plasma. Libraries of platelet RNAs were created separately
for long RNAs after ribosomal depletion and for small RNAs from total RNA, followed by
next-generation sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; Platelets in both groups demonstrated RNA expression
profiles characterized by absence of leukocyte-specific transcripts, high expression of
well-known platelet transcripts, and in total 6,343 consistently detectable transcripts.
Extensive statistical bioinformatic analysis yielded 12 genes with consistently differential
expression at a lenient FDR &amp;lt; 0.1, thereof 8 protein-coding genes and 2 genes with known
expression in platelets (MACF1 and ITGB3BP). Three of the four differentially expressed
noncoding genes were YRNAs (RNY1, RNY3, and RNY4) which were all downregulated in DM.
23 miRNAs were differentially expressed between the two groups.
Of the 13 miRNAs with decreased expression in the diabetic group,
8 belonged to the DLK1–DIO3 gene region on chromosome 14q32.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; In this study, uncontrolled DM had a remote impact on different components of the platelet transcriptome.
Increased expression of MACF1, together with supporting predicted mRNA-miRNA interactions as well as
reduced expression of RNYs in platelets, may reflect subclinical platelet activation in uncontrolled DM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">In a new manuscript Thomas Nührenberg et al. found that “Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus Has No Major Influence on the Platelet Transcriptome”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “The Transcription Factor ETV1 Induces Atrial Remodeling and Arrhythmia.”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/02/CarolinRommel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;The Transcription Factor ETV1 Induces Atrial Remodeling and Arrhythmia.&quot;" /><published>2018-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/02/CarolinRommel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/02/CarolinRommel/">&lt;p&gt;Carolin Rommel et al. found that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.313036&quot;&gt;“The Transcription Factor ETV1 Induces Atrial Remodeling and Arrhythmia”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/Hompage_ETV1-02.png&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;The Transcription Factor ETV1 Induces Atrial Remodeling and Arrhythmia&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for using Galaxy and congratulation to Carolin and her team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Structural and electrophysiological remodeling of the atria are recognized consequences of
sustained atrial arrhythmias, such as atrial fibrillation. The identification of underlying key molecules
and signaling pathways has been challenging because of the changing cell type composition during structural
remodeling of the atria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, the aims of our study were (1) to search for transcription factors and downstream
target genes, which are involved in atrial structural remodeling, (2) to characterize the significance
of the transcription factor ETV1 (E twenty-six variant 1) in atrial remodeling and arrhythmia, and (3)
to identify ETV1-dependent gene regulatory networks in atrial cardiac myocytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods and results:&lt;/strong&gt; The transcription factor ETV1 was significantly upregulated in atrial tissue from patients with permanent
atrial fibrillation. Mice with cardiac myocyte-specific overexpression of ETV1 under control of the myosin
heavy chain promoter developed atrial dilatation, fibrosis, thrombosis, and arrhythmia. Cardiac myocyte-specific
ablation of ETV1 in mice did not alter cardiac structure and function at baseline.
Treatment with Ang II (angiotensin II) for 2 weeks elicited atrial remodeling
and fibrosis in control, but not in ETV1-deficient mice. To identify ETV1-regulated genes,
cardiac myocytes were isolated and purified from mouse atrial tissue. Active cis-regulatory
elements in mouse atrial cardiac myocytes were identified by chromatin accessibility
(assay for transposase-accessible chromatin sequencing) and the active chromatin modification
H3K27ac (chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing). One hundred seventy-eight genes
regulated by Ang II in an ETV1-dependent manner were associated with active
cis-regulatory elements containing ETV1-binding sites.
Various genes involved in Ca2+ handling or gap junction formation
( Ryr2, Jph2, Gja5), potassium channels ( Kcnh2, Kcnk3), and genes implicated in atrial fibrillation
( Tbx5) were part of this ETV1-driven gene regulatory network. The atrial ETV1-dependent transcriptome
in mice showed a significant overlap with the human atrial proteome of patients with permanent atrial fibrillation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; This study identifies ETV1 as an important component in the pathophysiology
of atrial remodeling associated with atrial arrhythmias.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Carolin Rommel et al. found that “The Transcription Factor ETV1 Induces Atrial Remodeling and Arrhythmia”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enthusiastic Response to the First ELIXIR-NL Galaxy Training Course in the Netherlands</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/01/elixirnl-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enthusiastic Response to the First ELIXIR-NL Galaxy Training Course in the Netherlands" /><published>2018-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/01/elixirnl-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/11/01/elixirnl-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;An ELIXIR-NL training course entitled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biosb.nl/education/course-portfolio/bioinformatics-for-translational-medicine-using-galaxy/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bioinformatics for Translational Medicine using Galaxy: see it, do it, teach it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was held on October 17 - 19, 2018 in Amsterdam. Participants were enthusiastic about the course contents, and particularly interested in the link of using Galaxy workflows for training and teaching. For this workshop we used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu&quot;&gt;European Galaxy server&lt;/a&gt; via their wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.eu/tiaas&quot;&gt;Training Infrastructure as a Service (TIaaS)&lt;/a&gt; setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop consisted of two parts, which were separately targeting two groups of people: 1) Biomedical &amp;amp; translational medicine researchers/students who are keen on bioinformatics and 2) educators in the “bio” domain who would like to start using Galaxy in their courses as an introduction to Bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, a series of bioinformatics topics were taught in the Galaxy environment and the application of Galaxy into teaching has triggered interest and good response from the attendees. The follow-up feedback from the attendees is very positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full list of topics covered in this training course can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy-2018.bioinformatician.science&quot;&gt;the course webpage&lt;/a&gt; and all the training materials are available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://training.galaxyproject.org&quot;&gt;Galaxy training materials website&lt;/a&gt; (also suitable for self-study!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course was organized by members of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dtls.nl/community/interest-groups/galaxy-interest-group/&quot;&gt;DTL Galaxy Interest Group&lt;/a&gt;, more specifically by Chao (Cico) Zhang (VU), Sanne Abeln (VU), Anton Feenstra (VU), Saskia Hiltemann (ErasmusMC), Mateusz Kuzak (DTL) and Celia van Gelder (DTL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big &lt;em&gt;thank you!&lt;/em&gt; to the GalaxyEU team for providing the TIaaS service; it saved us a lot of time in preparation, and everything ran very smoothly on the day, and the team were on standby throughout the workshop to help in case we encountered any issues, it was a big factor in the success of the workshop, thanks a lot!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><category term="tiaas" /><summary type="html">An ELIXIR-NL training course entitled Bioinformatics for Translational Medicine using Galaxy: see it, do it, teach it! was held on October 17 - 19, 2018 in Amsterdam. Participants were enthusiastic about the course contents, and particularly interested in the link of using Galaxy workflows for training and teaching. For this workshop we used the European Galaxy server via their wonderful Training Infrastructure as a Service (TIaaS) setup.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Training Infrastructure Feedback from Maria Doyle</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/31/tiaas-feedback/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training Infrastructure Feedback from Maria Doyle" /><published>2018-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/31/tiaas-feedback</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/31/tiaas-feedback/">&lt;p&gt;We recently had the privilege of using the usegalaxy.eu’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.eu/tiaas&quot;&gt;Training
infrastructure as a Service (TIaaS)&lt;/a&gt; for our course on “Introduction to
Galaxy and RNA-seq” at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.petermac.org&quot;&gt;Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre&lt;/a&gt; in Melbourne,
Australia. Our own infrastructure was undergoing an upgrade and our
planned workshop was going to be delayed but thanks to the TIaaS we were
able to go ahead and run our workshop. All went smoothly and the feedback
was very positive with 100% saying they would recommend the course to
colleagues. A big thanks to the Galaxy EU team for providing this great
resource.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><category term="tiaas" /><summary type="html">We recently had the privilege of using the usegalaxy.eu’s new Training infrastructure as a Service (TIaaS) for our course on “Introduction to Galaxy and RNA-seq” at the Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre in Melbourne, Australia. Our own infrastructure was undergoing an upgrade and our planned workshop was going to be delayed but thanks to the TIaaS we were able to go ahead and run our workshop. All went smoothly and the feedback was very positive with 100% saying they would recommend the course to colleagues. A big thanks to the Galaxy EU team for providing this great resource.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New article ‘Selbst ist der Forscher: Big-Data-Analysen leicht gemacht’</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/30/Laborpraxis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New article 'Selbst ist der Forscher: Big-Data-Analysen leicht gemacht'" /><published>2018-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/30/Laborpraxis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/30/Laborpraxis/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laborpraxis.vogel.de/selbst-ist-der-forscher-big-data-analysen-leicht-gemacht-a-768506&quot;&gt;“Selbst ist der Forscher: Big-Data-Analysen leicht gemacht”&lt;/a&gt;,
a new German article written by The Freiburg Galaxy Team about our service and our work was published in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laborpraxis.vogel.de&quot;&gt;Laborpraxis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Die Analyse teils mühselig erhobener Daten geben Forscher nur ungern aus der Hand. Doch in Zeiten von Big Data kann genau diese Aufgabe einen in IT weniger versierten Lebenswissenschaftler an seine Grenzen bringen. Hochkomplexe Programme ohne Informatikkenntnisse selbst anwenden? Der neue Galaxy Europe Server macht das nun möglich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/laborpraxis.png&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;Article in Laborpraxis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">“Selbst ist der Forscher: Big-Data-Analysen leicht gemacht”, a new German article written by The Freiburg Galaxy Team about our service and our work was published in the Laborpraxis.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heinz tools for network analysis over transcriptomics datasets</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/17/heinz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heinz tools for network analysis over transcriptomics datasets" /><published>2018-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/17/heinz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/17/heinz/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ls-cwi/heinz&quot;&gt;Heinz&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm for searching an optimal subnetwork from a bigger network. It can be applied to biological networks like gene regulation and protein-protein network to pinpoint the subnetwork of interest. We are pleased to announce that Heinz tools have been integrated into the Galaxy platform and are available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy.eu/?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu%2Frepos%2Fiuc%2Fheinz%2Fheinz_scoring&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the training material for Heinz is also ready in Galaxy training network: &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/transcriptomics/tutorials/network-analysis-with-heinz/slides.html&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/transcriptomics/tutorials/network-analysis-with-heinz/tutorial.html&quot;&gt;Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, which can be used for self-learning or teaching purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Heinz is an algorithm for searching an optimal subnetwork from a bigger network. It can be applied to biological networks like gene regulation and protein-protein network to pinpoint the subnetwork of interest. We are pleased to announce that Heinz tools have been integrated into the Galaxy platform and are available on our server.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorial of the Month: “Galaxy 101”, selected by Yvan Le Bras</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/15/totm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorial of the Month: &quot;Galaxy 101&quot;, selected by Yvan Le Bras" /><published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/15/totm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/15/totm/">&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy community is developing and maintaining a collection of tutorials that are designed to be interactive and are built around Galaxy: &lt;a href=&quot;https://training.galaxyproject.org&quot;&gt;https://training.galaxyproject.org&lt;/a&gt;. To help highlight our tutorials and the training effort of the community, a member of the community will select every month one tutorial and explains in the &lt;em&gt;Galactic Blog&lt;/em&gt; why they select this tutorial. This month, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxyproject.org/blog/2018-10-totm/2018-10-cotm-yvan-le-bras&quot;&gt;Galaxy contributor of the Month!&lt;/a&gt;, Yvan Le Bras, selects and presents a tutorial: &lt;a href=&quot;http://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/introduction/tutorials/galaxy-intro-101/tutorial.html&quot;&gt;“Galaxy 101”&lt;/a&gt;, from the topic &lt;a href=&quot;http://galaxyproject.github.io/training-material/topics/introduction/&quot;&gt;“Introduction to Galaxy Analyses”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">The Galaxy community is developing and maintaining a collection of tutorials that are designed to be interactive and are built around Galaxy: https://training.galaxyproject.org. To help highlight our tutorials and the training effort of the community, a member of the community will select every month one tutorial and explains in the Galactic Blog why they select this tutorial. This month, the Galaxy contributor of the Month!, Yvan Le Bras, selects and presents a tutorial: “Galaxy 101”, from the topic “Introduction to Galaxy Analyses”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New article ‘Datenanalyse mit dem Galaxy Server’</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/Laborjournal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New article 'Datenanalyse mit dem Galaxy Server'" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/Laborjournal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/Laborjournal/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laborjournal.de/rubric/tricks/tricks/trick213.lasso&quot;&gt;“Datenanalyse mit dem Galaxy Server”&lt;/a&gt;, a German article written by The Freiburg Galaxy Team about our service and our work was published in the Laborjournal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">“Datenanalyse mit dem Galaxy Server”, a German article written by The Freiburg Galaxy Team about our service and our work was published in the Laborjournal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Paper on “Endothelial cell mineralocorticoid receptors oppose VEGF-induced gene expression and angiogenesis”</title><link href="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/AchimLother/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Paper on &quot;Endothelial cell mineralocorticoid receptors oppose VEGF-induced gene expression and angiogenesis&quot;" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/AchimLother</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://galaxyproject.eu/posts/2018/10/10/AchimLother/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1530/JOE-18-0494&quot;&gt;“Endothelial cell mineralocorticoid receptors oppose VEGF-induced gene expression and angiogenesis”&lt;/a&gt; by Achim Lother et al. was published in Journal of Endocrinology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulation to Achim and his team!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">“Endothelial cell mineralocorticoid receptors oppose VEGF-induced gene expression and angiogenesis” by Achim Lother et al. was published in Journal of Endocrinology.</summary></entry></feed>