<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-23T16:56:03+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/</id><title type="html">Galaxy Europe</title><subtitle>The European Galaxy Instance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Genome Annotation Reloaded</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/11/genome-annotation-reloaded/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Genome Annotation Reloaded" /><published>2018-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/11/genome-annotation-reloaded</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/11/genome-annotation-reloaded/">&lt;p&gt;During the last month the Galaxy team has put a lot of effort into updating the Genome Annotation tools and has included new tools that will change how you work with your Genome in silico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tool-updates&quot;&gt;Tool Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We updated &lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/antismash/antismash/4.1&quot;&gt;AntiSmash&lt;/a&gt;, a tool for genome-wide identification, annotation and analysis of secondary metabolite biosynthesis gene clusters, to the latest version 4.1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BLAST databases are up-to-date&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/crs4/prokka/prokka/1.12.0&quot;&gt;Prokka&lt;/a&gt;, a complete prokaryotic genome annotation pipeline, has been updated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and &lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/roary/roary/3.10.2&quot;&gt;Roary&lt;/a&gt;, a pangenome pipeline from our Australian friends to quickly generate a core gene alignment from gff3 files was integrated as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/augustus/augustus/3.2.3&quot;&gt;Augustus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/bgruening/glimmer3/glimmer_knowlegde-based/0.2&quot;&gt;Glimmer&lt;/a&gt; for gene prediction and &lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/gubbins/gubbins/0.1.0&quot;&gt;Gubbins&lt;/a&gt; for recombination detection in bacteria as well as many others saw updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;circos&quot;&gt;Circos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2018-02-12-circos.png&quot; alt=&quot;The circos tool in action, showing a snippet of a plot.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tool we would especially like to highlight is new Galaxy wrapper for &lt;a href=&quot;http://genome.cshlp.org/content/19/9/1639&quot;&gt;Circos&lt;/a&gt;.
Saskia Hiltemann from Erasmus MC (Leiden University), in collaboration with our own E. Rasche, have &lt;a target=&quot;_top&quot; href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/root?tool_id=toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/repos/iuc/circos/circgraph/0.9-RC2&quot;&gt;integrated Circos into Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, finally making it
possible to create beautiful production quality plots interactively in your browser, or automatically as part of a workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s annotate some Genomes – Any feedback welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">During the last month the Galaxy team has put a lot of effort into updating the Genome Annotation tools and has included new tools that will change how you work with your Genome in silico.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Disseminating Metaproteomic Informatics Capabilities and Knowledge Using the Galaxy-P Framework</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/01/metaproteomics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Disseminating Metaproteomic Informatics Capabilities and Knowledge Using the Galaxy-P Framework" /><published>2018-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/01/metaproteomics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/02/01/metaproteomics/">&lt;p&gt;Clemens and the GalaxyP team have published a new article about metaproteomics and Galaxy. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdpi.com/2227-7382/6/1/7&quot;&gt;Learn more about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of microbial communities, also known as the microbiome, on human health and the environment is receiving increased attention. Studying translated gene products (proteins)
and comparing metaproteomic profiles may elucidate how microbiomes respond to specific environmental stimuli, and interact with host organisms. Characterizing proteins expressed by a
complex microbiome and interpreting their functional signature requires sophisticated informatics tools and workflows tailored to metaproteomics. Additionally, there is a need to
disseminate these informatics resources to researchers undertaking metaproteomic studies, who could use them to make new and important discoveries in microbiome research. The Galaxy
for proteomics platform (Galaxy-P) offers an open source, web-based bioinformatics platform for disseminating metaproteomics software and workflows. Within this platform, we have
developed easily-accessible and documented metaproteomic software tools and workflows aimed at training researchers in their operation and disseminating the tools for more widespread
use. The modular workflows encompass the core requirements of metaproteomic informatics: (a) database generation; (b) peptide spectral matching; (c) taxonomic analysis and (d)
functional analysis. Much of the software available via the Galaxy-P platform was selected, packaged and deployed through an online metaproteomics “Contribution Fest“ undertaken by a
unique consortium of expert software developers and users from the metaproteomics research community, who have co-authored this manuscript. These resources are documented on GitHub and
freely available through the Galaxy Toolshed, as well as a publicly accessible metaproteomics gateway Galaxy instance. These documented workflows are well suited for the training of
novice metaproteomics researchers, through online resources such as the Galaxy Training Network, as well as hands-on training workshops. Here, we describe the metaproteomics tools
available within these Galaxy-based resources, as well as the process by which they were selected and implemented in our community-based work. We hope this description will increase
access to and utilization of metaproteomics tools, as well as offer a framework for continued community-based development and dissemination of cutting edge metaproteomics software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/proteomes-06-00007-ag.png&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; alt=&quot;metaproteomics workflow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.mdpi.com/2227-7382/6/1/7&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; type=&quot;application/xhtml+xml&quot; /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Clemens and the GalaxyP team have published a new article about metaproteomics and Galaxy. Learn more about it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Distinct epigenetic programs regulate cardiac myocyte development and disease in the human heart in vivo</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/Gilsbach_NatCom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distinct epigenetic programs regulate cardiac myocyte development and disease in the human heart in vivo" /><published>2018-01-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/Gilsbach_NatCom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/Gilsbach_NatCom/">&lt;p&gt;Congratulation to Ralf Gilsbach et al. from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.uni-freiburg.de/pharmakologie/ii&quot;&gt;Hein group&lt;/a&gt;
for their great new paper entiteled
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-02762-z&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Distinct epigenetic programs regulate cardiac myocyte development and disease in the human heart in vivo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/media/2018-01-30-Gilsbach_NatCom.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; alt=&quot;Genic CpG demethylation of cardiac myocyte genes.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epigenetic mechanisms and transcription factor networks essential for differentiation of cardiac myocytes have been uncovered. However, reshaping of the epigenome of these terminally differentiated cells during fetal development, postnatal maturation, and in disease remains unknown. Here, we investigate the dynamics of the cardiac myocyte epigenome during development and in chronic heart failure. We find that prenatal development and postnatal maturation are characterized by a cooperation of active CpG methylation and histone marks at cis-regulatory and genic regions to shape the cardiac myocyte transcriptome. In contrast, pathological gene expression in terminal heart failure is accompanied by changes in active histone marks without major alterations in CpG methylation and repressive chromatin marks. Notably, cis-regulatory regions in cardiac myocytes are significantly enriched for cardiovascular disease-associated variants. This study uncovers distinct layers of epigenetic regulation not only during prenatal development and postnatal maturation but also in diseased human cardiac myocytes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">Congratulation to Ralf Gilsbach et al. from the Hein group for their great new paper entiteled Distinct epigenetic programs regulate cardiac myocyte development and disease in the human heart in vivo.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We are now part of COST (CA16212)!</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/COST/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We are now part of COST (CA16212)!" /><published>2018-01-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/COST</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/30/COST/">&lt;p&gt;We are part of COST &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cost.eu/COST_Actions/ca/CA16212&quot;&gt;Impact of Nuclear Domains On Gene Expression and Plant Traits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cost.eu&quot;&gt;COST&lt;/a&gt; is an intergovernmental framework consisting in 36 Member States and a Cooperating State. This allows researchers from these countries to embark upon networking opportunities by participating in science and technology networks called COST Actions. If you are working with plants or have any questions don’t hesitate to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are part of COST Impact of Nuclear Domains On Gene Expression and Plant Traits</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next Galaxy Workshop on HTS data analysis in September 2018</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/26/Galaxy-workshop-9.2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next Galaxy Workshop on HTS data analysis in September 2018" /><published>2018-01-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/26/Galaxy-workshop-9.2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/26/Galaxy-workshop-9.2018/">&lt;p&gt;Because many people already asked: The autumn Galaxy Workshop on high-throughput data analysis will take place from 17.-21.9.2018 here in Freiburg.
Registration will be open from mid of April 2018 on. Save the date!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Because many people already asked: The autumn Galaxy Workshop on high-throughput data analysis will take place from 17.-21.9.2018 here in Freiburg. Registration will be open from mid of April 2018 on. Save the date!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Freiburg Galaxy Team has open positions!</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/openpositions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freiburg Galaxy Team has open positions!" /><published>2018-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/openpositions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/openpositions/">&lt;p class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/134305289@N03/31768905991/in/album-72157671198874931/&quot; title=&quot;Untitled&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/366/31768905991_508703bbeb_k.jpg&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-freiburg-galaxy-team-is-looking-for-2-postdoctoral-researchers&quot;&gt;The Freiburg Galaxy Team is looking for 2 Postdoctoral researchers.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Freiburg Galaxy Team works on software development for biomedical high-throughput sequencing data. We currently have open positions on different projects varying from programming to applied data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideal candidates have a PhD in informatics, computational biology or bioinformatics, a strong proficiency in UNIX, Python and JS, and proficiency in software development. A strong background in HTS data analysis and/or RNA research and interest in new technologies (containers) is desired. Candidates must have excellent verbal and written communication skills (English).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer the chance to work with leading, cutting edge technologies both in IT and computational biology and give you the opportunity to broaden your skills using open source technologies within a bioinformatics context. The University of Freiburg cares about the development of professional and personal skills and gives you the chance to work in one of the highest ranked scientific research organizations in the world. Come and join our team and contribute to this joint effort and work in a young and international environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positions are for initially 2 years with the possibility of extension. The salary will be determined in accordance with TVL-E13 (100 %).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further information: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bioinf.uni-freiburg.de/&quot;&gt;Bioinformatics Uni Freiburg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/galaxy-freiburg/people/&quot;&gt;Freiburg Galaxy Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send your application including a motivation letter, CV, certificates, and 3 references latest until 15.2.2018 via email to Anika Erxleben (bioinf-jobs@informatik.uni-freiburg.de)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galaxy Workshop - Registration is closed!</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/Galaxy-workshop-2.2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galaxy Workshop - Registration is closed!" /><published>2018-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/Galaxy-workshop-2.2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/18/Galaxy-workshop-2.2018/">&lt;p&gt;Due to the high number of applicants for the next Galaxy workshop from 26.02.-02.03.2018, we close the registration.
Participants will be selected from the applicants until 02.02.2018.
The next workshop will take place in September 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="training" /><summary type="html">Due to the high number of applicants for the next Galaxy workshop from 26.02.-02.03.2018, we close the registration. Participants will be selected from the applicants until 02.02.2018. The next workshop will take place in September 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASaiM - an environment to analyze intestinal microbiota data</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/17/ASaiM/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASaiM - an environment to analyze intestinal microbiota data" /><published>2018-01-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/17/ASaiM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/17/ASaiM/">&lt;p&gt;New generation of sequencing platforms coupled to numerous bioinformatics tools has led to rapid technological progress in metagenomics and metatranscriptomics to investigate complex microorganism communities. Nevertheless, a combination of different bioinformatic tools remains necessary to draw conclusions out of microbiota studies. Modular and user-friendly tools would greatly improve such studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We therefore developed ASaiM, an Open-Source framework dedicated to microbiota data analyses. ASaiM integrates a comprehensive set of microbiota related &lt;a href=&quot;http://asaim.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tools/index.html#framework-tools&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://asaim.readthedocs.io/en/latest/workflows.html#framework-workflow&quot;&gt;predefined and tested workflows&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to microbiota analyses. ASaiM offers then sophisticated analyses to scientists without command-line knowledge and a powerful framework to easily and quickly explore microbiota data in a reproducible and transparent environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASaiM is also available as a Docker Galaxy flavour, but tools and workflows can be tested here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more on &lt;a href=&quot;http://asaim.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&quot;&gt;ASaiM’s homepage&lt;/a&gt; or via its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/09/04/183970&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workflows&quot;&gt;Workflows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several &lt;a href=&quot;http://asaim.readthedocs.io/en/latest/workflows.html&quot;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt; has been developed for ASaiM and are available on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/u/berenice/w/asaim-shotgun-workflow&quot;&gt;Analysis of raw metagenomic or metatranscriptomic shotgun data&lt;/a&gt;: The workflow quickly produces, from raw metagenomic or metatranscriptomic shotgun data, accurate and precise taxonomic assignations, wide extended functional results and taxonomically related metabolism information&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/media/2018-01-17-asaim_main_workflow.png&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; alt=&quot;ASaiM workflow&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assembly of metagenomic data with two workflows, each one using one of each of the well-performing assemblers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/u/berenice/w/asaim-metagenomic-assembly-with-megahit&quot;&gt;MEGAHIT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/u/berenice/w/asaim-metagenomic-assembly-with-metaspades&quot;&gt;MetaSPAdes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis of metataxonomic data with &lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/u/berenice/w/asaim-qiime-illumina-overview-tutorial&quot;&gt;QIIME - Illumina Overview tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://galaxy.uni-freiburg.de/u/berenice/w/asaim-ebi-metagenomics-workflow-30&quot;&gt;Running as in EBI metagenomics (3.0)&lt;/a&gt; to reproduce locally analyses made in EBI Metagenomics website, without having to wait for availability of EBI Metagenomics or to upload any data on EBI Metagenomics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;embed src=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/09/04/183970.full.pdf&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot; /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">New generation of sequencing platforms coupled to numerous bioinformatics tools has led to rapid technological progress in metagenomics and metatranscriptomics to investigate complex microorganism communities. Nevertheless, a combination of different bioinformatic tools remains necessary to draw conclusions out of microbiota studies. Modular and user-friendly tools would greatly improve such studies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High-resolution TADs reveal DNA sequences underlying genome organization in flies</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/16/tads/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High-resolution TADs reveal DNA sequences underlying genome organization in flies" /><published>2018-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/16/tads</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/16/tads/">&lt;p&gt;New manuscript by Fidel Ramirez et al. about “High-resolution TADs reveal DNA sequences underlying genome organization in flies”
was published today. Want to learn HiC data analysis? Try HiCExplorer in your tool menue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;multiple-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/media/hicexplorer_2018_01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; alt=&quot;High-resolution TAD boundaries in flies.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite an abundance of new studies about topologically associating domains (TADs), the
role of genetic information in TAD formation is still not fully understood. Here we use our
software, HiCExplorer (https://hicexplorer.readthedocs.io) to annotate &amp;gt;2800 high-resolution (570
bp) TAD boundaries in Drosophila melanogaster. We identify eight DNA motifs enriched at
boundaries, including a motif bound by the M1BP protein, and two new boundary motifs. In
contrast to mammals, the CTCF motif is only enriched on a small fraction of boundaries
flanking inactive chromatin while most active boundaries contain the motifs bound by the
M1BP or Beaf-32 proteins. We demonstrate that boundaries can be accurately predicted
using only the motif sequences at open chromatin sites. We propose that DNA sequence
guides the genome architecture by allocation of boundary proteins in the genome. Finally, we
present an interactive online database to access and explore the spatial organization of fly,
mouse and human genomes, available at http://chorogenome.ie-freiburg.mpg.de.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">New manuscript by Fidel Ramirez et al. about “High-resolution TADs reveal DNA sequences underlying genome organization in flies” was published today. Want to learn HiC data analysis? Try HiCExplorer in your tool menue!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Combinatorial omics analysis reveals perturbed lysosomal homeostasis in collagen VII-deficient keratinocytes.</title><link href="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/13/kerstin-mcp-paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Combinatorial omics analysis reveals perturbed lysosomal homeostasis in collagen VII-deficient keratinocytes." /><published>2018-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/13/kerstin-mcp-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://usegalaxy-eu.github.io/posts/2018/01/13/kerstin-mcp-paper/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcponline.org/content/early/2018/01/11/mcp.RA117.000437&quot;&gt;“Combinatorial omics analysis reveals perturbed lysosomal homeostasis in collagen VII-deficient keratinocytes”&lt;/a&gt;
by Kerstin Thriene et al. was published today in Molecular and Cellular Proteomics. Thanks to Kerstin, Jörn and Collegues for this great collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extracellular matrix protein collagen VII is part of the microenvironment of stratified epithelia and critical in organismal homeostasis.
Mutations in the encoding gene COL7A1 lead to the skin disorder dystrophic epidermolysis bullosa (DEB), are linked to skin fragility and
progressive inflammation-driven fibrosis that facilitates aggressive skin cancer. So far, these changes have been linked to mesenchymal
alterations, the epithelial consequences of collagen VII loss remaining under-addressed. As epithelial dysfunction is a principal
initiator of fibrosis, we performed a comprehensive transcriptome and proteome profiling of primary human keratinocytes to generate
global and detailed images of dysregulated epidermal molecular pathways linked to loss of collagen VII.
These revealed downregulation of interaction partners of collagen VII on mRNA and protein level, but also increased
abundance of S100 pro-inflammatory proteins in primary DEB keratinocytes. Increased TGF-β signaling due to loss of
collagen VII was associated with enhanced activity of lysosomal proteases in both keratinocytes and skin of collagen VII-deficient individuals.
Thus, loss of a single structural protein, collagen VII, has extra- and intracellular consequences, resulting in inflammatory
processes that enable tissue destabilization and promote keratinocyte-driven, progressive fibrosis.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><summary type="html">“Combinatorial omics analysis reveals perturbed lysosomal homeostasis in collagen VII-deficient keratinocytes” by Kerstin Thriene et al. was published today in Molecular and Cellular Proteomics. Thanks to Kerstin, Jörn and Collegues for this great collaboration.</summary></entry></feed>